

Homepage:

adhikaar.github.

Address:

24 DDA Flats, Pocket-1, Sector-5, Dwarka New Delhi -75.

Phone

+91-995-380-9852, +91-991-157-8604

Email:

adi.newdelhi@gmail.com

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in Backend development using NodeJS+Express, NestJS & Django+DRF frameworks and Frontend development using Angular, React, Ionic & Flutter frameworks.

Experienced in building scalable web projects using AWS Services, Akamai CDN, and databases like MySQL/PostgreSQL, Redis, DynamoDB, and Cassandra.

Well-versed in numerous languages including JavaScript, Typescript, Python, Dart, C++, Java.

Qualifications

B.Tech (Computer Sc. & Engineering)	INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, GUWAHATI	CGPA - 8.94
Higher Secondary (CBSE)	MOTHER'S INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL	88%
Matriculation (CBSE)	MOTHER'S INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL	81%

Skills

Backend Development

- NodeJS + Express, NestJS
- Django Framework (with DRF)
- Firebase

Frontend Web Development

Angular2+, React, Bootstrap4, Javascript (ES6) + Typescript, HTML5, CSS

Frontend Mobile App Development

• Flutter Framework, Ionic 5 Framework

Databases

• MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Redis, Cassandra, MongoDB

Cloud Platforms & Devops

- AWS (EC2, S3, Cloudfront, Route53, IAM, VPCs, Load Balancers & ASGs, RDS, ElastiCache, Pinpoint, EKS, Cloudwatch and CloudTrail, Lambdas, Athena, Rekognition)
- CI/CD (Docker, Kubernetes Orchastration, EKS, GitHub, Jenkins, Travis CI, AWS CodeDeploy)
- Akamai (Edge DNS, NetStorage CDN, Adaptive Media Delivery)
- Monitoring using ELK Setup and and Cloudwatch Dashboards

Languages & Tools

- Javascript ES6, Typescript, Dart, Python, C++, Java OOP, HTML5, CSS
- Broadcasting and Transcoding (FFMPEG, RTMP, HLS, WebRTC, Agora)
- Git, MySQL Workbench, VS Code & Atom IDE, Android Studio, Jira & Slack

Experience

Backend Lead, Rooter Technologies Pvt Ltd

(Oct 2020-Present)

Leading the backend development team that manages our Apps with a user base of more than 15 Million. (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.threesixteen.app)

We have our in-house Live broadcasting setup built using Nginx RTMP servers, transcoding and recording streams using FFMPEG. The streams are ingested in RTMP format and served out in HLS using Akamai CDN and Adaptive Media Delivery services. Static video and image content are stored in S3 with a layer of Akamai Net Storage over it. Our architecture includes cluster of NodeJS and Django microservices running under auto-scaling groups behind Load Balancers, interacting using Rest APIs and AWS SQS queues. We use MySQL, DynamoDB, Cassandra, Redis and Firebase as our databases. The transcoding servers run as Kubernetes Jobs on EKS. The frontend webapp is built using React (https://rooter.gg) and we have native Android and IOS apps.

I am managing various 3rd party integrations including CleverTap, PayTM Payments and Payouts, AWS Pinpoint, GupShup, PayTM Mini App, Agora, AWS IVS, TrueCaller Login SDK, Yellow Messenger, etc.

• Mobile App Development Consultant, Newgen Software Technologies Ltd (Sep 2020-Mar 2021)

Developed and deployed hybrid apps for KCB (Kenya Commercial Bank) and FBN (First Bank Nigeria) which were built using Newgen's NEMF framework. This included writing JS code interfacing with the Cordova based APIs to build hybrid Android and IOS apps as well as deploying these to Playstore and Appstore respectively. Oracle's Websphere server was used as the backend over which Newgen's iBPS framework was run which provided the Rest APIs. In addition to application development I was also part of the team that directly interacted with the client and fixed bugs and catered to the customization requirements in the UAT stage.

Full Stack Web Developer

(Jul 2016-Aug 2020)

Developed Websites and Apps for a variety of startups and companies mainly using Angular 2+ and React with Bootstrap, Ionic, Flutter for frontend and NodeJS+Express, Django (+DRF) and Firebase for backend. The projects used MySQL, Redis, DynamoDB databases and were hosted on the AWS Cloud.

Managed Full Stack Web Development for companies like Sassy Networks Pvt Ltd, Statistify Market Research Pvt Ltd, DrTangri's Healthcare, Precision Smiles Clinic, Kreativ Droit Pvt Ltd, Delvens Pvt Ltd, DocSoft Solutions, TiffinQnQ Pvt Ltd, IITians Page Pvt Ltd.

• Intern in the Office of the Advisor to CM, Govt. of NCT Delhi

(Feb-May 2015)

Had been in-charge of restructuring and managing the Database and Website of the Public Grievance Management System of GNCTD in collaboration with the NIC team.

Founder and Director at Way2IIT Tutorials, Guwahati

(2009 - 2013)

Provided coaching classes to students from normal as well as under privileged backgrounds for exams like IIT JEE, AIEEE and Medical Exams and organized competitive exams for motivating students.

Intern in Dept of CSE, Concordia University, Canada

(May-July 2007)

Had worked in the area of Networking and Security under Prof. J.W. Atwood and developed a model for UMTS networks on NS2 simulator software.